# **AFRASIYAB (AFROKK) KHAN**

hi@afrokk.dev | LinkedIn.com/in/afrasiyab-k | GitHub.com/Afrokk | www.afrokk.dev

## **SUMMARY**

Upcoming **Software Engineering** grad with 7 years of experience in the tech industry, **managing a 1.7M subs YT channel**, **former founder of a tech news website**, and an avid freelancer with **works featured in Forbes**, **Uber**, and **more**.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, C, SQL (Postgres), HTML/CSS, SASS

Frameworks: React, Node.js, Flask, Vue.js, Next.js, Nuxt, Express, Bootstrap

Tools: Git, Docker, Jira, REST APIs, CI/CD, Adobe Suite, Figma

### **EXPERIENCE**

**Creative Design Manager** 

March 2019 - Present

*YouTube (@xeetechcare)* 

Remote

- Directing a **1.7 million subscriber** YouTube channel to produce tech content for a worldwide audience.
- Managing renowned brands including Samsung, Google, Chevrolet, and more across diverse industries.
- Produced over **500** videos of current tech, ranging from **smartphones**, **computers**, and **electric vehicles**.
- Implemented effective **SEO strategies** resulting in up to **+40% increase in views** from high CPM regions.

## **Lead Teaching Assistant**

January 2022 - Present

uWindsor School of Computer Science

Windsor, ON

- Mentored 100s of students in **four major Computer Science courses** in learning the course material, publishing study guides, code reviews, and answering queries.
- Conducted workshops with over 200 students to teach Computer Science tools, including C, Java OOP, SQL, OS
  programming including multithreading, and network socket concepts.

**Co-founder**May 2016 - February 2019 *GeeksULTD Malaysia* 

- Established and piloted GeeksULTD.COM, a technology/gaming-based website for 3 years.
- Accelerated website load times by optimizing JavaScript & CSS files and integrating CDN technologies such as Cloudflare and BunnyCDN, resulting in up to 2x faster load times.
- Published over 550 articles, reviews, and editorials related to computers, technology, and gaming.
- Collaborated with Samsung, Logitech, MSi, and more to publish over 30 product reviews and editorials.

## **EDUCATION**

# **University of Windsor**

Windsor, ON

Bachelors in Computer Science, Minor in Comm., Media & Film | GPA: 3.9/4.0 | President's List

May. 2021 - December. 2023

### **PROJECTS**

<u>litmus.tools</u> | TypeScript, React, WebAssembly, JavaScript, Vercel | <u>GitHub</u>

January 2023

- Developed a full-stack web app using React, TypeScript, and WebAssembly.
- Integrated data from the **US National Bureau of Economic Research** to provide users with accurate calculations and insights of their savings, earnings, and taxes, all based on their **individual** ZIP codes.
- Deployed via Vercel's CI/CD pipeline to www.litmus.tools.

# **afrokk.dev** | JavaScript, React, NextJS 13, TypeScript, Sanity CMS, SASS | GitHub

May 2023

- My full-stack personal developer portfolio built from scratch using JavaScript, React (NextJS 13), TypeScript, Sanity CMS (backend), and SASS, to showcase my profile and projects.
- Implemented advanced features like light/dark mode, lazy loading, custom lightbox, carousels, and scroll bars.

## **Automobile Dealership DBMS** | C, SQL, Shell | GitHub

May 2023

- Built a serverless Database Management System in C with full CRUD functionality, for an automobile dealership.
- Efficiently tracks active inventory, customers, repairs, work orders, and other essential operational data.

Plus Airport Simulator (Java), OpenQASM: A Technical Article (using Quantum Composer), Vintage Autohaus, and more.

## **EXTRA CURRICULARS**

<u>CS Games 2023</u> Seguenay, QC